

Matthew Arderne

DATA ENGINEER

2 Carney Place, Coldharbour Lane, Brixton, London, United Kingdom

□ (+44) 737-879-1160 |
□ m.arderne@gmail.com |
♠ mattarderne.com

Summary

I am an experienced Data Engineer specialising in Data Integration. I am very comfortable with Data Integration, SQL and ETL. I've also managed reporting tools, analytics projects and machine learning data requirements.

I have a background in Industrial Engineering, and I began my career in ERP implementation before moving into the realm of reporting, data systems and data engineering, thus I have an excellent understanding of business analytics, reporting and business processes.

My personal interests include hackathons, running, sailing and climbing.

I do not require UK visa sponsorship.

Work Experience

DenodoLondon, UK

DATA ENGINEER May. 2018 - PRESENT

- Provide professional implementation and system health check services to Denodo customers.
- Provide online customer support services through support site relating to query performance tuning, configuration optimisation and integration processes.
- Online tutorial and education content development.

GetSmarter Cape Town, South Africa

DATA ENGINEER

Nov. 2016 - May. 2018

- Planned and implemented the Denodo Platform on AWS at GetSmarter.
- Drove adoption of Denodo as primary data source for all data consumption including Tableau, Zoho reporting, and Reporting Data Warehouse, as well as for 10 Analysts and Data Scientists.
- Defined and built the semantic layer in Denodo, which integrated multiple data sources (Redshift, MySQL, S3, PostgreSQL, Salesforce API) into a final semantic layer, that helped analysts and data scientists access data autonomously using common business terms.
- Responsible for all maintenance, enhancements and development performed on the Denodo Platform, as well as ensuring uptime adherence to business Service Level Agreements.
- Master Data Management and system data migrations.
- · ETL and data warehousing.
- · AWS infrastructure management.

Devil's Peak Brewing Company

Cape Town, South Africa

Jan. 2015 - Nov. 2016

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

- Managed the implementation of Acumatica ERP, managing a team of two external consultants and two internal resources to deliver the project successfully and within budget and allocated time frame.
- Implemented Power BI reporting and visualization for all essential reports.
- Through implementing the reporting infrastructure for this project I fully realized my interests in data and have since actively pursued this direction.

Adapt IT Cape Town, South Africa

BUSINESS ANALYST

Jun 2014. - Jan. 2015

• User acceptance testing for implementation of fuel delivery tracking integration with SAP for Local Oil Major.

• Microsoft CRM implementation and maintenance.

Skills

Data EngineeringData Integration, SQL, ETL, Python, Linux, Feature Engineering.Data SystemsDenodo, Tableau, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS, Redshift, Git, Docker.

Business Systems Acumatica ERP, Salesforce.com.

Analytics Reporting Automation, KPI Development, Predictive Analytics.

August 30, 2018 Matthew Arderne · Curriculum Vitae

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology MIT

BIG DATA AND SOCIAL ANALYTICS

Online Short Course Aug. 2017 - Oct. 2017

• Analyze big data to better understand and predict human networks and behaviors in social structures.

University of Oxford - Said Business School

OXFORD BLOCKCHAIN STRATEGY PROGRAMME

• Blockchain product strategy development, ideation and feasibility study.

Online Short Course

Mar. 2018 - Apr. 2018

Stellenbosch University

Stellenbosch, South Africa

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (B.ENG.) - INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

Jan. 2009 - Dec. 2012

• Final year project: Polyurethane micro-gripper utilizing van-der-Waals forces in micro-assembly.

Extracurricular Activity

Ikamva Youth Cape Town, S.A.

STUDENT MENTOR Jan. 2017 - Dec. 2017

• Mentored High School students to prepare for their final exams and bursary applications.

Facebook Developer Circles

Cape Town, S.A

MEMBER

Jun. 2017 - Sept. 2017

• Attended lecture series relating to use of PyTorch for Deep Learning.

Honors & Awards

2018 2nd Place, TNVA Future Cities Hackathon London, U.K

2017 Winning Team, Digital McKinsey Future-Hack Johannesburg, S.A.

2017 Panelist, Denodo Data Virtualization Product Advisory Council London, U.K